# **Derrick Kyei**

Phone: (678) 457-4534 Email: derrick.kyei50@gmail.com Address: Silver Spring, MD 20906 Website: https://derrickdk.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

A results driven Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in implementing advanced technologies and business solutions. Well versed in Java, C#, Python, SQL, Angular,, Typescript, JavaScript, and CSS programming languages. Worked in coordinating with technical teams and stakeholders to manage large scale projects and deployment environments. Constantly updating personal and professional technical skills with certifications.

#### **EDUCATION:**

The University Of Georgia — Franklin College of Arts and Sciences

Athens, GA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

January 2018 - December 2019

Overall GPA: 3.58

Honors & Awards: HOPE Scholarship Recipient

**Georgia State University — Perimeter College** 

Decatur, GA

Associate of Science, Computer Science

January 2015 – December 2017

Overall GPA: 3.79

Honors & Awards: Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society, National Society of Collegiate Scholars

#### **CERTIFICATIONS:**

AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

**Proficient**: Java, Python, Angular, Typescript, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL **Experience**: C#, C, C++, NodeJs, AngularJs, Bash/Shell, PowerShell

CI/CD Tools: Azure Pipelines

**Build Tools**: Maven

Operating Systems: Unix, Linux, Windows, MacOS

Other: Agile, Scrum, Visual Studio Code, REST API, Microsoft Azure, Postman, Git, CodeCloud, Jira, SQL Server

Management Studio

#### **SOFT SKILLS:**

Leadership, Communication, Problem Solving, Organization, Time Management, Strategic Planning, Design Thinking

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

# Azure DevOps/Databricks

Alpharetta, GA

Senior Software Engineer

January 2023 - March 2024

- Experienced in DevOps/Agile operations in developing spark applications using PySpark SQL in databricks for data ETL and aggregation from multiple file formats for analyzing and transforming data.
- Experienced in data extraction of schemas, corrupt record handling, and code transformations.

• Good understanding of medallion architecture data design pattern used to logically organize data in datalake house with the goal of incrementally and progressively improving the structure and quality of data in each layer of the architecture bronze silver gold layer tables using PySpark.

# **Azure DevOps/Secrets Management**

Alpharetta, GA

Senior Specialist Software Engineer

November 2021 - December 2022

- Experienced in IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS services such as virtual machines, virtual networks, resource groups, auto-scaling, power-shell, and automation.
- Experienced in working on DevOps/Agile operations process and tools area unit testing, automation, build and release automation environment.
- Created infrastructure for applications in Azure using Terraform. Building and Automating CICD pipelines for different applications.
- Experienced with version control tools such as GIT and Bitbucket. Comprehensive knowledge of source control concepts including branches, tags, pull requests, commits, and merges.
- Supported tickets using Java to manage secrets in Azure key vault to maintain security amongst Java applications.

HR Technology Atlanta, GA

Software Engineer

March 2021 - November 2021

 Migrated CompConnect, a legacy application, rewritten from cold fusion to Angular, Typescript, and NodeJs into the Azure Cloud. The project consisted of multiple business functions that were in scope to be migrated.

Project Atlas Atlanta, GA

Software Engineer

January 2020 - March 2021

- Used Angular, Typescript, and NodeJs to develop a full-stack web based application for technicians to use on residential product installs.
- Tasked with bug fixes, enhancements, and adding new features.
- Demoed new features to clients and product owners that helped with cost savings.

TDP app Atlanta, GA

Software Engineer Intern

June 2019 - August 2019

- Used AngularJs and NodeJs to develop a full-stack social communication app for TDP which helped increase communication, collaboration, and grow individual network.
- Used C# and Agile development with intern innovation challenge team to develop a virtual reality app that leveraged 5G technology to tackle the issue of customer churn to help increase sales and improve customer service by anticipating needs and interest.

#### **LEADERSHIP:**

## **Diversity & Inclusion**

- Tasked with media planning, organizing, and overseeing events within DE&I at AT&T.
- Designed monthly newsletter with information presented by newsletter team.

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS:**

Fertilizer App CSCI 4950 Directed Study **University of Georgia** 

December 2019

- Used React Native to create a IOS and Android mobile application that allowed users to use their mobile devices to make quick calculations.
- Conducted user testing on application and incorporated results into direction of project.

Messenger App University of Georgia

CSCI 4060 Mobile Software Development

December 2019

- Used Java to create a full-stack native mobile android application leveraging firebase cloud technology to develop SMS application.
- Conducted user testing and incorporated results into direction of project.

# **Movie Rating Prediction Application**

**University of Georgia** 

CSCI 4370 Database Management

Spring 2019

• Used Java and SQL to pull in existing data from IMDB database to find the best fit regression modal to accurately predict genre ratings.

Project Intercept Atlanta, GA

Full Stack Developer

November 2017

- Attended Goodie Nation's Hackathon to focus on producing startups to reduce violence by 40% by the year 2020 locally and globally.
- Team developed web-based communications platform to produce services to survivors of human trafficking